Guide to the University Christian Movement in New England Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
University Christian Movement in New England Records
1918-1990
RG 88
Yale University Divinity School Library
20
(49 boxes)
The papers include correspondence, reports and minutes, printed material, and financial material. They constitute the official archive of the organization from its formation in 1967. The papers contain information about the local Christian ministries' programs of various colleges and universities in New England and document issues that were of concern to college students during the turbulent late 1960s and 1970s. These papers fit into a line of documentation at YDSL of religious work among college and university students, including the archives of the YMCA-Student Division, Student Christian Movement in New England, New England Commission for United Ministries in Higher Education, National Campus Ministry Association, and United Ministries in Higher Education. The University ChristianMovement in New England is anon-denominational campus ministry organization formed in 1967 to continue the work of the Student Christian Movement in New England. The StudentChristian Movement was formed in 1934 by the YMCA, YWCA, and various Protestant denominations to promote cooperative religious work among college and university students.
University Christian Movement in New England
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the UCMNE.
Biographical / Historical
In 1934, the Student Christian Movement in New England came into being under the auspices of the YMCA and YWCA. As the years progressed, most Protestant denominations joined in support of the SCM through direct financial contributions or by contributing staff. Through the 1950s SCM units flourished on most campuses throughout New England. The SCM supported the workof these local units, facilitated regional conferences, and related to both national and international expressions of student Christian life. The early 1960s found most of the SCM units dissolving as students became more politicized and gravitated toward other organizations, often feeling that the Church was not responding to the urgent needs of the time. In 1967 the SCM decided to become a regional member of the national University Christian Movement and officially changed its name to the University Christian Movement in New England.
During the years 1968 to 1970 a two-year experiment was undertaken to develop an organizational style for the organization that would encourage student initiative in the creation of local action projects for social change. The major Protestant denominations supported this two-year experiment of the UCM via their involvement in United Ministries in Higher Education (UMHE). Efforts were made to build a communication network among various student and youth groups in New England who were not in the main stream of the church and to provide services to these groups that would help their local work. In 1970 two new women staff members were hired to give impetus to the new style of operation.
The UCM supported a variety of projects during the 1970s. In Maine, it supported the Franco-American Resource Group at the University of Maine and the Penobscot Native American Nation. In Vermont it supported the People's Free Clinic. In New Hampshire it supported the New Hampshire People's Press, which worked with local groups around community issues such as racism in the high schools and the Vietnam War. In Connecticut it supported the Women's Abortion Referral Service and the Women's Research Project, both based in New Haven. In Massachusetts it supported the For the People organization, which coordinated college students' activities on their campuses, such as women's centers and Black Student Unions.
The bulk of the documentation in this record group ends around 1975; the UCMNE still exists and additional archives will be added in the future.
Scope and Contents
These records form one more piece in the complicated, evolving picture of Protestant religious work among college and university students in America. They also provide insight into the college scene in general during the turbulent late 1960s and early 1970s, documenting various programs and organizations that sought to reform American society. There is considerable overlap between these archives and the archives of predecessor and related groups also held at the Yale Divinity Library, but new parts of the story are revealed here. Files of UCM associate Helen Morton, which were received with these archives, have been organized into a separate record group, YDSL Record Group 133.
The Organization and Policy Records of Series I include some material related to predecessor organizations, including the Student Christian Movement in New England. For more extensive SCMNE records, see YDSL Record Group 57. The "Historical Information" folder in Series Iincludes a few documents tracing the UCM's activities after 1975, but most records documenting the period from 1975 to the present remain with the UCM. Series II, documenting the programmatic work of the UCM, is divided into topical, regional, and state files.
The Related Organizations of Series III include the Student Christian Movement of Canada, United Ministries in Higher Education, denominational groups, and miscellaneous other organizations with which the UCMNE interacted. Additional UMHE records are available in YDSL Record Groups 54 and 104. Collected Materials in Series IV include documentation arranged according to topic that documents the range of concerns and program interests of the UCMNE, as well as publications of various non-UCM groups. The final series contains extensive financial records.
Arrangement
I. Organization and Policy Records, 1920-1990
II. Program, Regional and State Files, 1968-1981
III. Related Organizations, 1929-1979
IV. Collected Materials, 1955-1980
V. Financial Material, 1952-1975
College students -- Religious life; Universities and colleges -- Religion; Student Christian Movement in New England; University Christian Movement in New England
- Organization and Policy Records, 1920-1990; Series I
  - Predecessor Organizations
    - Technology Christian Association (MIT), 1920-1962 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
    - TCA Constitution and By-laws (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - TCA Photographs, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - TCA Proposed name change, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Student Christian Movement, 1950-1967, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6-10)
    - SCM Administrative Committee, 1960-1967 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - SCM Alumni News, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - SCM Anderson, K. Brooke Correspondence, 1960-1967 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - SCM Annual Representative Assembly, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - SCM Collected Materials, 1934-1959 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - SCM Committee Materials, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - SCM Contributions, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 17-20)
    - SCM Criticisms, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - SCM Directory, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - SCM General Committee Materials, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - SCM Keeywadin Camp, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - SCM Leadership Training Seminar, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - SCM National Student Staff Annual Reports, 1950-1952 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - SCM New Folk Hymnal, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - SCM O-At-Ka, 1947-1957 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - SCM O-At-Ka Conference Slides, n.d. (Box 4)
    - SCM Postal Information, 1949-1957 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - SCM Regional Staff Council, 1952-1957 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - SCM Ross, Wallace M. Correspondence, 1961-1963 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - SCM-WSCF, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - UCM Office Files
    - Alumni and Friends, 1970-1975 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Articles and By-laws, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Board of Trustees' Minutes, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Contact Lists, 1970-1975 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Executive Committee Meeting, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Funding Information (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Funding Proposal, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Funding Proposal, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 40-41)
    - Funding Proposal, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 42-46)
    - Funding Proposal, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 47-49)
    - General Committee Meetings, 1967-1972 (Box 7, Folder 50-53)
    - General Committee Meetings, 1973-1975 (Box 8, Folder 54-56)
    - Historical Information/Annual Summary Statements, 1934-1990 (Box 8, Folder 57)
    - Insurance, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 58)
    - Mailing LISTS, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 59)
    - Membership Committee, 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 60)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 61)
    - Miscellaneous Documents, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 62)
    - Name Change from SCM, 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 63)
    - Personnel, 1967, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 64)
    - Program and Strategy Committee, 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 65)
    - Progress Reports, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 66)
    - Project Lists, 1968-1975 (Box 8, Folder 67-69)
    - Regional Staff Council, 1967-1968 (Box 9, Folder 70)
    - Rhodes, Lynn Correspondence, 1968-1973 (Box 9, Folder 71)
    - Search Committee, 1968-1976 (Box 9, Folder 72)
    - Staff Position Search, 1972-1973 (Box 9, Folder 73-74)
    - Staff Report, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 75)
    - Steering Committee, 1970-1975 (Box 9, Folder 76-78)
    - Travel Grant Guidelines, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 79)
- Program, Regional and State Files, 1968-1981; Series II
  - Program Files
    - Adhoc Committee for Theological Reflection, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 80)
    - New England Ecumenical Conference (Box 10, Folder 81)
    - Quebec Workers' Movement, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 82)
    - Southwest Georgia Project, 1970-1972 (Box 10, Folder 83)
    - Summer Work Project, 1979-1981 (Box 10, Folder 84)
    - Urban Planning Aid, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 85)
    - Women's Gathering, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 86)
    - Women's Project: Funding, 1970-1972 (Box 10, Folder 87)
  - Regional Files
    - East, 1968-1976 (Box 10, Folder 88)
    - Midwest, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 89)
    - New England, 1976-1977 (Box 10, Folder 90-91)
    - South, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 92)
    - West, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 93)
  - State Files
    - CT: Bridgeport, 1970-1972 (Box 10, Folder 94)
    - CT: Hartford, 1970-1975 (Box 10, Folder 95)
    - CT: Middletown, 1968-1970 (Box 10, Folder 96)
    - CT: New Britain, 1970-1976 (Box 11, Folder 97)
    - CT: New Haven, 1970-1971 (Box 11, Folder 98)
    - CT: New Haven, 1971-1972 (Box 11, Folder 99)
    - CT: New Haven's Women's Project, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 100)
    - CT: Storrs, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 101)
    - DE: Wilmington, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 102)
    - MA: Amherst, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 105)
    - MA: Amherst's Everywomen's Center, 1972-1974 (Box 11, Folder 106)
    - MA: Boston-Cambridge, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 107)
    - MA: Bridgewater, 1970-1974 (Box 12, Folder 108)
    - MA: Brockton, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 109)
    - MA: Chelsea, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 110)
    - MA: Dartmouth, 1973-1974 (Box 12, Folder 111)
    - MA: New Bedford, 1972-1975 (Box 12, Folder 112)
    - MA: Springfield, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 113)
    - MA: Summer Projects, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 114)
    - ME: Women's Project, 1971-1972 (Box 11, Folder 103)
    - ME, 1972-1974 (Box 11, Folder 104)
    - NH, 1970-1973 (Box 12, Folder 115)
    - NH: "Sister", 1973 (Box 12, Folder 116)
    - RI, 1968-1972 (Box 12, Folder 117)
    - RI: Women's Center, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 118)
    - VT, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 119)
    - VT: Area Schools, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 120)
- Related Organizations, 1929-1979; Series III
  - Student Christian Movement of Canada
    - Records, 1972-1976 (Box 13, Folder 121-123)
  - United Ministries in Higher Education
    - General, 1970-1972 (Box 13, Folder 124-126)
    - General, 1973-1975 (Box 14, Folder 127-129)
    - UMHE: MA, 1972-1980 (Box 14, Folder 130)
    - UMHE: NY, 1973-1974 (Box 14, Folder 131)
    - UMHE: RI, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 132)
    - Articles and By-laws (Box 15, Folder 133)
    - Campus Ministers, 1969-1972 (Box 15, Folder 134)
    - Communications Team, 1969-1970 (Box 15, Folder 135)
    - Community Colleges, 1973-1975 (Box 15, Folder 136)
    - Development Committee, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 137)
    - Executive Committee, 1968-1973 (Box 15, Folder 138)
    - Finances, 1972-1973 (Box 15, Folder 139)
    - Financial Statements, 1968-1973 (Box 15, Folder 140)
    - Fundraising Team, 1972-1973 (Box 15, Folder 141)
    - International Staff Committee, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 142)
    - Massachusett's Commission, 1973-1974 (Box 15, Folder 143-144)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 145)
    - MOTIVE, 1968-1970 (Box 15, Folder 146)
    - National Commission, 1968-1972 (Box 15, Folder 147)
    - Personnel, 1968-1970 (Box 15, Folder 148)
    - Probe, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 149)
    - Program and Strategy Committee, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 150)
    - Project Proposals and Guidelines, 1970, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 151)
    - Publications, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 152)
    - Self-Study Reports, 1968-1970 (Box 16, Folder 153)
    - Self-Study: Rhode Island Commission, 1972-1973 (Box 16, Folder 154)
    - Self-Study: Service Team, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 155)
    - Self-Study: Worcester Campus Ministry, 1972-1979 (Box 16, Folder 156)
    - UMHE-UCM Conference on Liberation, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 157)
  - Denominational Material
    - American Baptist, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 158)
    - Community Church in Boston, 1974-1976 (Box 16, Folder 159)
    - Episcopal Church, 1971-1973 (Box 16, Folder 160)
    - Episcopal Church: Youth Initiative Program, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 161)
    - First Church in Cambridge (UCC), 1972-1978 (Box 16, Folder 162)
    - Lutheran Church, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 163)
    - Massachusetts Baptist Foundation, 1971-1976 (Box 17, Folder 164)
    - Massachusetts Congregational Christian Conference, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 165)
    - Massachusetts Council of Churches, 1962, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 166)
    - Old Cambridge Baptist Church, 1956-1972 (Box 17, Folder 167)
    - Presbyterian Church in the USA, 1973-1974 (Box 17, Folder 168)
    - United Church of Christ, 1971-1974 (Box 17, Folder 169)
    - United Methodist Board of Missions, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 170)
    - United Methodist Board of Global Ministries, 1971-1975 (Box 18, Folder 171)
    - United Methodist Board of Higher Education, 1974-1976 (Box 18, Folder 172)
    - United Methodist Campus Ministers and Chaplains, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 173)
    - United Methodist Council on Youth, 1971-1974 (Box 18, Folder 174)
    - United Methodist Fund for Reconciliation, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 175)
    - United Methodist Women's Caucus, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 176)
    - United Presbyterian Church of USA, 1971-1972 (Box 18, Folder 177)
  - Other Organizations
    - African Research Group, 1969-1972 (Box 18, Folder 177)
    - American Committee on Africa, 1977-1979 (Box 18, Folder 178)
    - Boston Community School, 1974-1975 (Box 18, Folder 179)
    - Boston Theological Institute, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 180)
    - Bread and Roses (Box 18, Folder 181)
    - Capital Area Action Movement, 1968-1970 (Box 19, Folder 182)
    - Catholic Committee on Urban Ministry, 1974-1975 (Box 19, Folder 183)
    - Center of Concern, 1974 (Box 19, Folder 184)
    - Chaplains' Association, 1968 (Box 19, Folder 185)
    - Christian Faith and Higher Education (Box 19, Folder 186)
    - Church Society for College Work, 1971-1974 (Box 19, Folder 187)
    - Commission for Radical Justice, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 188)
    - Community Change, Inc., n.d. (Box 19, Folder 189)
    - Corporate Examiner, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 190)
    - Cuban Resource Center (New York), 1971-1973 (Box 20, Folder 191)
    - Danforth Study of Campus Ministers, 1967-1969 (Box 20, Folder 192)
    - Grailville, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 193)
    - Ecumenical Campus Ministry Conference, 1973-1975 (Box 20, Folder 194)
    - Ecumenical Institute, 1964-1974 (Box 20, Folder 195)
    - Ecumenical Metropolitan Ministry, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 196)
    - Education for Action, 1971-1976 (Box 20, Folder 197)
    - Frontier Internship in Mission, 1961-1974 (Box 20, Folder 198)
    - Goddard College, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 199)
    - Haymarket Foundation, 1976-1979 (Box 21, Folder 200)
    - Hazen Foundation (Box 21, Folder 201)
    - International Ministry in Cambridge, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 202)
    - JSAC-Youth Ministries, 1971 (Box 21, Folder 203)
    - Jessie Smith Nayes Foundation, 1975-1976 (Box 21, Folder 204)
    - L.E. Moran Company, 1957-1958 (Box 21, Folder 205)
    - Mental Health Association, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 206)
    - National Campus Ministry Association, 1971-1974 (Box 21, Folder 207)
    - National Commission on Ethnic Minorities, 1939-1941 (Box 21, Folder 208)
    - National Conference on Catholic Bishops, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 209)
    - National Council of Churches, 1964-1975 (Box 21, Folder 210)
    - National Intercollegiate Christian Council, 1938 (Box 21, Folder 211)
    - National Institute for Campus Ministry, 1974-1976 (Box 21, Folder 212)
    - New England Field Council, 1929-1936 (Box 22, Folder 213)
    - New York Review Presentations, 1968 (Box 22, Folder 214)
    - Orthodox Campus Commission, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 215)
    - Puerto Rican Socialist Party, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 216)
    - Religious Coalition for Abortion Rights, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 217)
    - Southern Appalachian Ministry, 1973-1976 (Box 22, Folder 218)
    - Southern Africa: International Defense and Aid Fund, 1974-1975 (Box 22, Folder 219)
    - Submarine Church Action Movement, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 220)
    - World Affairs Council, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 221)
    - Women's Campus Ministry Caucus, 1972-1973 (Box 22, Folder 222)
    - Women's Caravan, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 223)
    - Women's National Abortion Action Coalition, 1970-1972 (Box 23, Folder 224)
    - World University Service, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 225)
    - YMCA, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 226)
    - YMCA: International Committee, 1965-1966 (Box 23, Folder 227)
    - Young World Development, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 228)
    - YWCA, 1956-1968 (Box 23, Folder 229-230)
- Collected Material, 1955-1980; Series IV
  - Topical Files
    - African Drought, 1974 (Box 24, Folder 231)
    - Apartheid, 1978-1980 (Box 24, Folder 232)
    - Black Economic Development Conference, 1969 (Box 24, Folder 233)
    - Black Manifesto, 1969 (Box 24, Folder 234-235)
    - Black Power, 1967-1968 (Box 24, Folder 236)
    - Brown Christian Association, 1955-1956 (Box 24, Folder 237)
    - Canada, 1968-1970 (Box 24, Folder 238)
    - China, 1976 (Box 24, Folder 239)
    - Christians for Socialism, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 240)
    - Church Investments, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 241)
    - Conscientious Objectors, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 242)
    - Conservative Organizations, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 243)
    - Corporate Responsibility, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 244)
    - Covenant Communities, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 245)
    - Cuba, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 246)
    - Dartmouth Christian Association, 1918-1950 (Box 25, Folder 247)
    - Dartmouth College, 1957-1966 (Box 25, Folder 248)
    - Education, 1969-1976 (Box 25, Folder 249)
    - Education: Free Universities, 1967-1972 (Box 25, Folder 250)
    - Education: University, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 251)
    - Funding Organizations (Box 26, Folder 252)
    - Guinea-Bissau, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 253)
    - Health, 1969-1972 (Box 26, Folder 254)
    - Imperialism/Capitalism, 1962-1974 (Box 26, Folder 255)
    - James Bay Project, 1973 (Box 26, Folder 256)
    - Middle East-General, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 257)
    - Middle East-Palestine, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 258)
    - Ministries to Blacks, 1972-1974 (Box 26, Folder 259)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 260)
    - Movie News, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 261-262)
    - Mozambique, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 263)
    - Namibia, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 264)
    - People Against Racism, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 265)
    - Puerto Rico, 1967-1974 (Box 28, Folder 266)
    - Quebec, 1965-1968 (Box 28, Folder 267)
    - Racism, 1968-1970 (Box 28, Folder 268-269)
    - South Africa, 1977-1980 (Box 28, Folder 270)
    - South Africa: Catalyst Project, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 271)
    - South African Liberation, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 272)
    - Southern Africa, 1973-1977 (Box 29, Folder 273)
    - Student Revolutions, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 274)
    - Taize, 1974-1975 (Box 29, Folder 275)
    - Theology of Liberation, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 276)
    - Theology and Politics Study Group, 1970-1971 (Box 29, Folder 277)
    - Women: Church and Theology (Box 30, Folder 278-280)
    - Women and Religion, 1972-1975 (Box 30, Folder 281-282)
    - Women's Center, 1970-1971 (Box 30, Folder 283)
    - Women's Conference Papers, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 284)
    - Women's Liberation, 1970-1971 (Box 31, Folder 285)
    - Youth-Adult Advisory Board, 1970-1971 (Box 31, Folder 286)
    - Zimbabwe, 1977-1978 (Box 31, Folder 287)
  - Non-UCM Publications
    - American Christians Toward Socialism (ACTS), 1977 (Box 32, Folder 288)
    - Agenda, 1978-1979 (Box 32, Folder 289)
    - Andover Newton Quarterly, 1978-1980 (Box 32, Folder 290)
    - American Reports, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 291)
    - Blue Print, 1975-1979 (Box 32, Folder 292)
    - CALA Newsletter (Community Action on Latin America), 1976-1979 (Box 32, Folder 293)
    - Center for Human Survival Newsletter, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 294)
    - Center for a Just Society, 1976-1977 (Box 32, Folder 295)
    - Chile Committee for Human Rights Newsletter, 1976-1978 (Box 32, Folder 296)
    - Christian Peace Conference or Christlichen Friedenskonferenz, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 297)
    - Christianity and Crisis, 1976-1979 (Box 33, Folder 298-299)
    - CLSA, 1977 (Box 33, Folder 300)
    - Colleague, 1978-1979 (Box 33, Folder 301)
    - Commentator, 1976-1977 (Box 33, Folder 302)
    - Connector (CCUM), 1979 (Box 33, Folder 303)
    - Connexion, 1973-1979 (Box 33, Folder 304-305)
    - Context, 1976-1977 (Box 33, Folder 306)
    - Conversations, Concerns and Challenges, 1976-1980 (Box 33, Folder 307)
    - Corporate Examiner, 1976-1979 (Box 34, Folder 308)
    - COSMEP, 1977-1978 (Box 34, Folder 309)
    - CPPAX, 1976-1978 (Box 34, Folder 310)
    - Criminal Justice Issues, 1977-1978 (Box 34, Folder 311)
    - CUSLAR Newsletter, 1978-1979 (Box 34, Folder 312)
    - Cuba Review, 1978-1979 (Box 34, Folder 313)
    - Disclosure, 1976 (Box 34, Folder 314)
    - Ecumenical News, 1978-1980 (Box 34, Folder 315)
    - Engage/Social Action, 1979-1980 (Box 34, Folder 316)
    - Eritrea In Struggle, 1969-1978 (Box 34, Folder 317)
    - El Espalda Mojada, 1976 (Box 34, Folder 318)
    - Fair Measure, 1978-1979 (Box 34, Folder 319)
    - The Feminist Press, 1977-1978 (Box 34, Folder 320)
    - The Fifth Commission, 1978-1980 (Box 34, Folder 321)
    - Food Conspiracy, 1978-1980 (Box 35, Folder 322)
    - Freedom Village, 1978-1980 (Box 35, Folder 323)
    - Gleanings, 1976 (Box 35, Folder 324)
    - Goddard-Cambridge, 1976-1977 (Box 35, Folder 325)
    - Gold Star Parents for Assembly, 1977 (Box 35, Folder 326)
    - Grand Jury Report, 1977-1979 (Box 35, Folder 327)
    - Guild Notes, 1976 (Box 35, Folder 328)
    - Haymarket News, 1974-1976 (Box 35, Folder 329)
    - Heraldo Cristiano, 1978 (Box 35, Folder 330)
    - Higher Education News Notes, 1976-1979 (Box 35, Folder 331)
    - Interim, 1976 (Box 35, Folder 332)
    - ICUIS, 1977 (Box 35, Folder 333)
    - IFCO News, 1973 (Box 35, Folder 334)
    - Interviews International Bulletin, 1979 (Box 35, Folder 335)
    - Korea Bulletin, 1976 (Box 35, Folder 336)
    - Liberation Support Movement, 1974-1978 (Box 35, Folder 337)
    - Macroscope, 1977-1978 (Box 35, Folder 338)
    - Mobilization for Survival, 1977 (Box 35, Folder 339)
    - National Campus Ministry Association, 1979 (Box 36, Folder 340)
    - New Beginnings, 1976-1978 (Box 36, Folder 341)
    - New England Human Rights Network, 1979 (Box 36, Folder 342)